<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IGD301: Vannvatthana Norng</title>
    <link>https://VannVatthana.github.io/vnorngSite/</link>
    <description>Recent content on IGD301: Vannvatthana Norng</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2024 </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://VannVatthana.github.io/vnorngSite/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Class Homework 5 : Evaluation of the Selection Technique</title>
      <link>https://VannVatthana.github.io/vnorngSite/posts/classhomework5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://VannVatthana.github.io/vnorngSite/posts/classhomework5/</guid>
      <description>In the Lab Homework 6, I talked about how I implemented Sloppy Robin to select the items at the supermarket. Here, I am going to talk about the evaluation of the technique. The task is to use this technique to select 20 supermarket items as fast as possible. I need 3 people (myself included) to evaluate on some criteria as follow:
Average time and Accuracy per session #Well, everyone seems to take quite some time to finish the task with not really high accuracy.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Homework 5 : Selection Pitch</title>
      <link>https://VannVatthana.github.io/vnorngSite/posts/labhomework5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://VannVatthana.github.io/vnorngSite/posts/labhomework5/</guid>
      <description>In Class Homework 4, I proposed three selection technique ideas what might be really fun to implement, but they are either too simple for the scope of the course or difficult and not suitable to implement for Oculus headset. So, I would like to propose a new selection technique, which I would call it Sloppy Robin.
Sloppy Robin #Sloppy Robin is a technique that makes use the scenario of shooting an arrows in real life.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class Homework 4: Selecting Objects in a Supermarket</title>
      <link>https://VannVatthana.github.io/vnorngSite/posts/classhomework4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 16:14:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://VannVatthana.github.io/vnorngSite/posts/classhomework4/</guid>
      <description>Grabbing and Teleportation #Goal: To make the shopping experience in visual supermarket to be intuitive and accessible.
How it works: Users use the teleportation technique to move to differents locations of the supermarket. Once arriving in the proximity to wanted items, they can physically reach out and grab those items using VR controllers.
VR TeleportationGrabbing Object (arm-reach)Evaluation:
The success of this technique is evaluated based on speed and easiness of the navigation by teleportation, and the precision of the grabbing interaction with objects.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class homework 3: Selection techniques</title>
      <link>https://VannVatthana.github.io/vnorngSite/posts/classhomework3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://VannVatthana.github.io/vnorngSite/posts/classhomework3/</guid>
      <description>The Flexible Pointer #The Flexible Pointer overcomes the limitations of conventional pointing methods by adopting a virtual flexible pointer that can bend and curve around obstacles. Therefore, it allows users to point objects that are partially or fully occluded by other objects.
Flexible Pointer bended around an objectReach: Infinite Users can point at objects anywhere in the virtual environment using Flexible Pointer. This is because the virtual pointer can be bent or flexed around objects, so there is no limit to how far it can reach.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Homework 4 : Roll-A-Ball in VR</title>
      <link>https://VannVatthana.github.io/vnorngSite/posts/labhomework4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://VannVatthana.github.io/vnorngSite/posts/labhomework4/</guid>
      <description>In Lab Homework 3, I made my first project Roll-A-Ball in Unity. This time, I will convert that project into a version that we can play in VR headsets.
You can find this project file on my Github https://github.com/VannVatthana/roll_a_ball_vr.
Roll-a-Ball VR #Set up the project #As usual, start by create a new 3D project (have a look at Lab Homework2 in case you forget). Since Oculus headset runs with Android, we need to build the project for Android device as well.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class Homework 2 : CAVE System</title>
      <link>https://VannVatthana.github.io/vnorngSite/posts/classhomework2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 16:46:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://VannVatthana.github.io/vnorngSite/posts/classhomework2/</guid>
      <description>What is CAVE System? #CAVE (Cave Automatic Virtual Environment) is a room-sized VR system that uses projectors to display images on all of the walls, floor, ceiling. This creates a completely immersive experience for the users so that they feel as if they are inside the virtual world. Display in CAVE systemDifferences between CAVE and HMD devices #CAVE : A room-sized VR system that uses projectors to display images on all walls, floor, and ceiling Creates a completely immersive experience for the user Typically used for scientific visualization, medical training, and entertainment.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class Homework 1: VR Fails</title>
      <link>https://VannVatthana.github.io/vnorngSite/posts/classhomework1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 01:18:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://VannVatthana.github.io/vnorngSite/posts/classhomework1/</guid>
      <description>In order to give the fully immersive experience of a virtual world, the VR headsets are designed so that users are completely isolated from the surrounding environment. This can cause users to harm themselves if there are a lot objects or people around them. Here are two different scenarios that could potentially lead to collisions or physical harm between the VR user and other people/objects and how you can overcome them.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Homework 3 : Unity Roll-A-Ball</title>
      <link>https://VannVatthana.github.io/vnorngSite/posts/labhomework3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://VannVatthana.github.io/vnorngSite/posts/labhomework3/</guid>
      <description>In this lab, we are going to build my first Unity project Roll-A-Ball. The step-by-step tutorial of this project can be found at Unity&amp;rsquo;s official website, make sure to choose the right version according to the one that you installed.
You can also find my project file from https://github.com/VannVatthana/roll_a_ball_v2020
Roll-A-Ball project #Assume that an empty 3D project is created (please look at Lab Homework2), There are 4 types of objects that are needed to be created for this project:</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Homework 1 : Set Up Blog</title>
      <link>https://VannVatthana.github.io/vnorngSite/posts/labhomework1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://VannVatthana.github.io/vnorngSite/posts/labhomework1/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog! My name is Vannvatthana NORNG, I am currently a 3rd year student at Télécom Paris. In this blog, I will cover about the progress of my virtual reality course IGD301: Human-Computer Interaction for Mixed Reality. I hope you enjoy it!</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Homework 2 : Set up Unity</title>
      <link>https://VannVatthana.github.io/vnorngSite/posts/labhomework2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://VannVatthana.github.io/vnorngSite/posts/labhomework2/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I am going to talk about how I set up unity for my upcoming labs and projects.
Unity Setup #First and foremost, download and install UnityHub from Unity&amp;rsquo;s website: https://unity.com/download Choose the one that is suitable for your operating system. After installing the application, it will look like this: This is where you can create the projects you want to work on, but before that, you need to install at least one Unity version first.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
