<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IGD301: Vannvatthana Norng</title>
    <link>https://VannVatthana.github.io/vnorngSite/</link>
    <description>Recent content on IGD301: Vannvatthana Norng</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2024 </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 16:14:46 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://VannVatthana.github.io/vnorngSite/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Class Homework 4: Selecting Objects in a Supermarket</title>
      <link>https://VannVatthana.github.io/vnorngSite/posts/classhomework4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 16:14:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://VannVatthana.github.io/vnorngSite/posts/classhomework4/</guid>
      <description>Grabbing and Teleportation #Goal: To make the shopping experience in visual supermarket to be intuitive and accessible.
How it works: Users use the teleportation technique to move to differents locations of the supermarket. Once arriving in the proximity to wanted items, they can physically reach out and grab those items using VR controllers.
VR TeleportationGrabbing Object (arm-reach)Evaluation:
The success of this technique is evaluated based on speed and easiness of the navigation by teleportation, and the precision of the grabbing interaction with objects.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class homework 3: Selection techniques</title>
      <link>https://VannVatthana.github.io/vnorngSite/posts/classhomework3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://VannVatthana.github.io/vnorngSite/posts/classhomework3/</guid>
      <description>The Flexible Pointer #The Flexible Pointer overcomes the limitations of conventional pointing methods by adopting a virtual flexible pointer that can bend and curve around obstacles. Therefore, it allows users to point objects that are partially or fully occluded by other objects.
Flexible Pointer bended around an objectReach: Infinite \ Users can point at objects anywhere in the virtual environment using Flexible Pointer. This is because the virtual pointer can be bent or flexed around objects, so there is no limit to how far it can reach.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class Homework 2 : CAVE System</title>
      <link>https://VannVatthana.github.io/vnorngSite/posts/classhomework2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 16:46:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://VannVatthana.github.io/vnorngSite/posts/classhomework2/</guid>
      <description>What is CAVE System? #CAVE (Cave Automatic Virtual Environment) is a room-sized VR system that uses projectors to display images on all of the walls, floor, ceiling. This creates a completely immersive experience for the users so that they feel as if they are inside the virtual world.
Differences between CAVE and HMD devices #CAVE : A room-sized VR system that uses projectors to display images on all walls, floor, and ceiling Creates a completely immersive experience for the user Typically used for scientific visualization, medical training, and entertainment.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class Homework 1: VR Fails</title>
      <link>https://VannVatthana.github.io/vnorngSite/posts/classhomework1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 01:18:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://VannVatthana.github.io/vnorngSite/posts/classhomework1/</guid>
      <description>Here are two different scenarios that could potentially lead to collisions or physical harm between the VR user and other people/objects and how you can overcome them.
Scenario 1 #The VR user is playing a game that requires them to move around in their real-world environment. They may not be paying attention to their surroundings and could bump into furniture, walls, or other people.
Possible solutions #Use a VR play area: Set up a designated VR play area that is free of obstacles.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
